givology.org 2010-06-25

# 

Givology has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this site.

We assure you that the identity of all who use this website is kept confidential: we do not rent, sell, or exchange your personal information and we will strive to be responsible in our management and cost-effective in our fund raising. We are continually working to ensure every dollar is used to its fullest for this purpose. Anything less would violate the trust we keep with you, with the children, schools, and communities we serve.

We are committed to the highest standard of stewardship excellence. We will exert every effort to honor any designation of preference you have stated.

**Collection and Use of Personal Information**

We collect personal information when you create an account or edit your account information and donate to a student/project. We also collect some technical information about your use of our website. This information is used to facilitate your use of the site and your donations, to contact you when necessary, and to improve your experience.

**Creating a Givology.com Account**

When you create an account on our website, we collect basic information about you - your name and email address. We collect additional personal information if you submit a profile or picture.

**Making a Donation**

When you make an online donation on Givology.com, we collect personal information such as your name, billing address, and email address, if you have not already provided these details. Credit card or bank account numbers are collected by a third-party payment vendor (Google Checkout). Use of your information is based on their terms of service and policies, which you should review. Givology will collect only your Givology account information and donation history. We do not collect or have access to the credit card numbers or bank account information our third-party vendors collect to process online transactions.

**Contests, Promotions, and Surveys**

Periodically, Givology may invite you to participate in contests, take advantage of special promotions, and complete online surveys. The information we collect from these contests, promotions, and surveys may be associated with your individual account in order to help us improve our website and services. This information will only be shared as described in this policy, and your answers to surveys will only be used in aggregate.

**Technical Information**

We collect some technical information about how you access and use our site. Cookies are small files that a website stores on your computer. We use cookies to collect information such as what type of browser you are using, the website from which you enter Givology.com, and the pages you view as you tour our site. We use this information to improve your experience and to help us compile aggregate statistics that allow us to make improvements in design and content to better serve you. An IP address is a number that is assigned to your computer when you are using the Internet. Like most websites, we identify your computer by its IP address. We use this to monitor information, such as the number of visitors that visit our website.

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

**Disclosure of Personal Information**

Under no circumstances will we rent or sell your personal information to third parties, including our field partners. The personal information we collect is used internally to process your donations, offer you services in connection with our website, communicate news and information Givology and the students/projects that you sponsor, provide customer service, and enhance and improve your donor experience. Givology reserves the right to record and display anonymous donation activity on the website.

Aside from the purposes described above, we will not disclose your personal information without your consent, unless: (1) we need to respond to a subpoena, court order or legal process; (2) an emergency situation requires disclosure before your permission can be obtained (e.g., situations involving potential threats to personal safety), or; (3) to protect our rights or property, or the rights or property of another person.

**Viewing and Updating Your Information on Givology.com**

You can access your account information at any time by going to the My Account page. You can make changes to your profile and update your account at any time. 

**Links to Other Websites**

Other websites, including those of our partners (links to which appear on Givology.com), have their own privacy policies. When you provide personal information at one of those sites, you are subject to the privacy policy of the operator of that site, not the Givology privacy policy. We encourage you to read that policy before submitting any personal information.

You should take additional steps to safeguard your personal information online. To learn more about how to protect yourself, visit the Federal Trade Commission website.

**Privacy Policy Updates**

Our privacy policy is regularly reviewed to make sure we continue to serve the privacy interests of our customers. If our information practices change materially, we will post the policy changes on the privacy page of this website to notify you of these changes. Please check our website periodically for more information on how we use the data we collect.

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please email us at [info@givology.org](mailto:info@givology.org) or write us at 3732 Locust Walk, Philadelphia, PA 19104.
